This is Anthony and we're going to talk about cleaning photo negatives.
First thing you want to do when your cleaning a negative is wear a glove.
It's kind of annoying.
Looks kind of silly but you know what?
It really helps.
You don't want to start cleaning something while your putting more dirt on what your cleaning.
Makes sense.
This is a negative I have.
Two and a quarter black and white negative.
Has a fine layer of filth on the negative.
I want to clean this negative.
Right here is what's called a anti static cloth.
In my opinion it's the best tool to use to clean negatives.
I personally don't like using caned air.
It's bad for the environment and a lot of times.
I find out that can air almost spits out condensation and that can actually ruin my negative.
So that's not good in my opinion.
So I'm going to use this cloth very simply I'm going to fold the cloth over and clean the negative.
Negatives usually have water marks, dust murks to some degree.
Scratches on them.
You want to avoid the scratches.
Everything else you can pretty much get off.
If this doesn't work with the cloth I go to anti static film cleaner.
The number one ingredient in all film cleaner.
Is isopropyl alcohol.
In my studio I just have a bit vat of isopropyl alcohol that I use.
I've had it for years a little alcohol, isopropyl alcohol.
On a cotton ball will clean almost any negative but I do like the film cleaner sometimes.
There's a little bit extra ingredient in it.
That just seems to work as a solvent a little bit better on my negatives.
There are two sides to a negative.
You have the emulsion side non emulsion side.
You want be extremely careful with the emulsion side of your negative.
That is the negative where layer of emulsion is on.
That actually gets exposed to light and makes your image.
If you scratch that.
Your basically going to have a negative that is going to have a scratch on it for life and your only going to be able to get that scratch off.
Via photo shop or a retouching job and that's starts to get very time consuming and very expensive.
So always treat your negatives with the utmost care and again this is really the first step that I like to use.
It's just this cloth.
They sell them at any photography store.
It's an anti static cloth they cost about ten bucks max.
So it's pretty affordable if you keep them in the little bag.
They'll last for years.